Fei Tian

Email: ftian@mum.ca

Tel: 709-986-6307

Address: 7 Calvin Ave

Software Developer Android Developer

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A highly resourceful technology savvy. Software developing and testing with experience in Java and Android SDK.

Web developing in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP. Committed to technological advancement and Developer role.

Proven experience and success working within application development environments, individually and as a team member.

Comprehensive understanding on development, design, testing, debugging and documentation of applications.

KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java (3 years)

Android SDK (2 years)

HTML (1 year)

Java Script (1 year)

CSS(1 year)

MySQL (1 year)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

C++, PHP, RESTful, third-party API(1 year) Eclipse, Android Studio, Dreamweaver, XAMPP, Github

PROFILES

https://franktian0906.github.io

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

June 2017- Dec2017

Sport Partner App (Android OS, PHP, MySQL)

 Developed the application 'Go Up', collected and recorded sport data of stairs climbing, and reflected the pattern of data on the visible line charts for the user

- Created client and server communication form on RESTful/ JSON
- Utilized the pressure sensor detector on mobile to periodically collect data statistics from users
- Embedded the third-party API which indicated data usage with MPAndroidChart library to perform the data pattern.
- Built the database by using the PHP to connect user data and commend on MySQL database.
- CLIENT CODE: https://github.com/FrankTian0906/ClimbingStairs
- SERVER CODE: https://github.com/FrankTian0906/ClimbStairs_Server

Take Home App (Android OS, MySQL)

Sept 2018

- Developed airline routes searching system by using the IATA city codes to create route suggestion page for users' review
- Utilized Local SQLite with 10000+ data sources, and created animation
- Embedded the third-party API on Google Map of Android API
- CODE: https://github.com/FrankTian0906/TakeHome

The Circuit Simulation System (Java)

January 2017

- Simulated circuit function for users to draw a circuit diagram by building gates and links; set input value for users to generate result;
- Used MVC design mode to construct the frame work
- Drew the variant circuit gates with JFrame library
- Created the automatic spot detection; drew the gates and links between each terminal
- Set signals to transport the command the output result
- CODE: https://github.com/FrankTian0906/CircuitSimulator

WORK EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant in Memorial university

Jan 2017 - Apr 2017

City of St. John's, NL

- Supervised students during lab class time and organized activities
- Worked closely with the lead TA to identify issues that students encountered and developed appropriate solutions
- Assisted with classroom instruction in Java Class; provided support and guidance to students

Technologies supporter in Inspur Inc.

Jan 2014 - Jul 2014

City of Taiyuan, China

- Installed and maintained the logistics system for clients
- Reported user's data to create the backed-up data
- Guided customers to operate the system and answered general inquires

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Volunteer, Lantern Festival

July 30th, 2016

City of St. John's, NL

- Installed the lanterns display.
- Supervised and directed motorists to the designated parking spaces and checked for parking permits.

EDUCATION

Master of Applied Science (Computer Engineering) GPA 3.7/4.0

Jan 2016 - Jan 2018

Memorial University, St. John's, NL

Bachelor of Computer Science (Network Engineering) GPA 8.1/10

Sept 2009 - Jul 2013

North University of China, Taiyuan City, China